Jalen Arms

Full-stack Software Developer

Jalenarms@outlook.com | Portfolio | Github

SKILLS

- Front-End: Blazor/Blazor WASM, JavaScript / TypeScript, React.is, Angular, SwiftUI
- Back-End: C# / .NET, Python, SQL Server
- Other Tools: Windows IIS, Azure, AGILE, Visual Studio Code, Git, CI/CD, XCode

ABOUT ME

I have been developing web applications for over three years in a variety of languages, with a strong focus on designing and implementing various types of APIs. I'm well-versed in frontend with technologies like Blazor, React.js, Angular, and also backend using ASP.NET Core, while also spending a lot of time in SQL Server for database development, allowing me to work on any area of the stack.

Beyond web development, I also have data engineering experience that helps me think about data modeling in a more holistic way and optimize how I design the interaction with said data. Insights to how data is reported on is a great way to understand how the quality and shape of data can drive a business' growth and success.

EDUCATION

University of Arizona Coding Bootcamp

Certified Full-stack Software Developer Certificate

EMPLOYMENT

Community Bridges Inc. - Software Developer/Data Engineer - (March 2023 - Current)

- Build and maintain HIPAA compliant web applications using Blazor WASM for client side development, .NET Web API for server-side development and class libraries to help share models across applications
- Designed a Domain-driven codebase where business logic, application logic, and use cases are all abstracted into their own corner of the repository
- Follow an AGILE development process that involves working with clients throughout the build process, going through a certain feature, or functionality and tailoring it to their needs as time goes and the application needs grow
- I created a framework for creating configurable Pdf documents that can be generated using generic shapes of data
- I write and maintain business logic in SQL Server using stored procedures, while also writing queries for refreshable reports
- I created a framework for taking a stored procedure and generating a C# class for the input parameters and a class for the shape of the output, and also the function that takes in the input

- class, calls the stored procedure and deserializes the results into a list of the output class
- I created a framework for creating configurable components, where you could have database records that control how the component behaves, such as how it gets data, what capabilities and access there is to updating or deleting the existing data and what data sources will be called when something is created, updated or deleted
- I create and maintain the application pools in IIS for hosting the client application and server application and set up a deployment pipeline to make it easy to update the production servers with the current version on the development server
- Utilize python to build programs for automating the insertion of large excel or csv files while manipulating and generalizing the data as needed
- Design automated backend tasks with python to solve the problem of needing to do tedious tasks on the computer, usually involving working with the local file system and any available network or sftp path

HotSpot – Lead IOS Developer - (November 2024 – Current)

- Implement a pre-designed interface, adding interaction to make the application dynamic
- Work with the Google Maps SDK to display an interactive map where events are displayed and can be drilled into using navigation.
- Design the data structure to compliment any ui requirements, and also any background data tasks, such as importing data from external systems

Signalizer.io – Lead Software Developer - (September 2023 – October 2023)

- Utilize Next.js to construct a web application that allows users access to real-time stock market and crypto coin news and pricing data
- Implemented Stripe to require the user to subscribe to a monthly plan before having access to the sensitive data
- Utilized Chart.js to enhance the user's view of the progression of data over time and implemented the logic to allow the user to control the time frames for which they view the data

StarHealth – Software Developer - (Nov 2022 – Jan 2023)

- Restructured database to improve functionality on the frontend
- Migrating the application over to a Next.js application, specifically a T3-Stack application that uses a tRPC API with prisma as an ORM to communicate with the database
- Added a directory page to allow users to search and filter through the mass amount of data in the database

REFERENCES

Angel Rodriguez (Senior Software Developer at BigTime Software) · 602-341-0796

Addison Albrecht (Front-End Web Developer at Northwestern Mutual) · 262-308-3338